opb.org 2018-10-05

# Privacy Policy . About | OPB

### **Acceptance of OPB Website Privacy Policy Terms and Conditions**

**Last updated: Dec. 1, 2017**

Oregon Public Broadcasting (“OPB”) is a nonprofit entity. Everything we do is intended to further our mission: “Giving voice to the community, connecting Oregon and its neighbors, illuminating a wider world.” We use your data to further our mission in two core ways: creating a personalized OPB experience for you and improving OPB for everyone. By understanding how you engage with OPB, we create better content for everyone – while ensuring that OPB remains member-supported and mission-driven.

This Privacy Policy describes how we handle information that OPB collects from you when you use our digital services, including our websites, apps, and newsletters. (Collectively, we refer to these as our “services.”) This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected through any other means, including in person, by phone, by mail or email you send to OPB, or data we acquire from third parties that is not a result of your interaction with our services. Most of the personal information we collect is voluntary, and you can always decide whether to provide certain personal information.

You may access many of OPB’s services without registering for an account or donating to OPB (we refer to donors as “Members”). We refer to unregistered users and users who have not donated to OPB as “Visitors.” The scope of data collected from Visitors is more limited than the data collected from Members and registered users. Where applicable, those distinctions are described throughout this Privacy Policy.

As a public media organization, OPB values transparency, and this Privacy Policy explains our practices in detail. OPB also values innovation, which means that we are always improving our services. New services may result in the collection of new information that is not explicitly described here. If we change our practices in material ways, we will post an updated Privacy Policy before the changes become effective.

This Privacy Policy explains the following:

I. Information OPB collects

II. How we use the information we collect from you

III. How we share your personal information

IV. Your choices for how we collect and use your personal information

V. How OPB protects your personal information

VI. Children’s privacy

VII. Your California privacy rights

VIII. Changes to this Privacy Policy

IX. How to contact us

### **I. Information OPB collects**

_OPB collects two types of information: information that can identify you individually (“personal information”), and aggregate or non-identifying information that does not identify you personally (“non-personal information”). We collect personal information in two ways. First, some users provide us with personal information by submitting it directly to OPB. Second, we – and trusted service providers working on our behalf – collect certain personal information automatically as you interact with our services. Non-personal information is also collected or generated automatically when you use the services._

**A. Personal information**

**1\. Personal information you provide to us**

When you become a Member, sign up for our communications, enter contests or drawings, order products online, submit content, and otherwise connect with us, you may provide OPB with personal information, such as:

  * _Contact information_ , including name, telephone number, address, and email address

  * _Payment card information_ (customers and Members)

  * _Checking account information_ (Members)
  * _User-generated content,_ including photos, videos, and audio recordings you submit, and Member testimonials

All of this information is provided voluntarily. Visitors may access a variety of OPB content without providing this type of personal information.

**2\. Personal information collected automatically**

When Visitors and other users interact with our services, we (or service providers on our behalf) may collect personal information automatically through technological measure. This includes:

_Personal information collected through tracking technologies_. Like many companies, OPB – and our service providers – use technologies, including “cookies” and “web beacons,” to automatically collect information about how you use the services. We use these tracking technologies to collect personal information, as well as non-personal information, as described in Section I-B below.

Cookies are small amounts of data that are stored within your Internet browser so it may   save and recognize your earlier browsing. Web beacons are web page elements that can recognize certain types of information on your computer or mobile device such as cookies and the time and date a page was viewed.

Personal information that may be collected via tracking technologies may include:

  * Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer or mobile device to the Internet;

  * Your computer or mobile device and connection information such as your browser type and version, operating system and platform (when linked with other identifiable information about you)

  * Your unique device identifier

You can delete cookie files from your hard drive, or avoid them altogether, by configuring your browser to reject them or to notify you when a cookie is being placed on your hard drive. Some features of the services will not function as intended if you reject cookies. Rejecting or deleting cookies does not affect web beacons.

**B. Non-personal information**

OPB uses the tracking technologies described above, as well as third-party tags and third-party analytics services, to collect and generate data about how Visitors, Members, and other users generally interact with our services. This non-personal information is either aggregated or does not identify you individually. Non-personal information includes:

  * Web pages that users visit

  * Date and time of each visit to the services

  * Amount of time spent using the services

  * Websites visited before and after using the services

  * Operating system and browser type

  * Social media analytics

  * Other usage and activity data, such as log files

At this time, OPB does not collect precise location data (e.g., data that can locate the actual physical location of you or your device). However, we track general location data (down to the neighborhood level) about the devices you use to connect with OPB.

### **II. How we use the information we collect from you**

_OPB uses your personal information primarily to further our core mission. It allows us to create a personalized experience for you and respond directly to your inquiries. We also use your personal information to improve OPB for everyone and grow our membership. By increasing membership, OPB can improve our content and continually expand our service offerings._

**A. Creating a personalized OPB**

  * _Delivering content you request (not applicable to Visitors)_. For example, we use your email address to send you newsletters and other content to which you’ve subscribed.

  * _Personalized experiences._ For example, your preferences are used to customize an audio playlist on our News app via the Discover tool. We may also use your generalized location, browsing history, or other preferences to deliver more relevant content and advertising to you through the OPB services and on third-party websites.
  * _Fulfilling product orders, sending thank-you gifts, and contacting you about your membership (not applicable to Visitors)._ We use your payment and shipping information to send you products that you order through our web store. When you become a Member, we use your shipping information to send thank-you gifts. We also may contact you just to say “thank you.” We may combine information we collect about you through the services with other information about you that we receive from third-party sources. For example, we may use a change of address or other list service to ensure that our records for your membership are accurate.

**B. Improving OPB**

  * _Soliciting donations_. For example, we may use your contact information to alert you when your membership has lapsed.

  * _Processing donations (not applicable to Visitors)_. For example, we may use your information to pre-populate web forms and streamline the donation process.

  * _Developing content._ For example, we study which content is most accessed and viewed (or heard) in order to develop content that we think will interest the community.

  * _Contacting you about submissions_. For example, if you submit a photo, we may use your contact information to request permission to use the image.

  * _Analysis and research_. We improve the services based on how you interact with them.

  * _Promoting OPB (not applicable to Visitors)_. We may send you email or mail to announce new services or features, or otherwise promote OPB.

  * _Protecting OPB_. We may use your information to protect the security and integrity of our services, to comply with court orders and legal processes, to enforce our Terms of Use, and for any other legal, business, or marketing purposes that are consistent with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

### **III. How we share your personal information**

_We sometimes share limited portions of your personal information with other nonprofit entities, including other public broadcasting organizations. We also share your personal information with service providers, but only to the extent required to deliver and improve our services. Other third parties may receive limited portions of your personal information, which they may use to send you relevant content and offers. In rare cases, OPB may share your personal information with successors (if we are restructured) or law enforcement (if legally required and only to the extent consistent with our integrity as a news organization). We will get your permission before sharing your personal information in any other way not described in this Privacy Policy. These restrictions don’t apply to non-personal information, which does not identify you individually._

**A. Third parties who receive your personal information**

**1\. NPR, PBS, and other affiliates**

OPB shares limited portions of your personal information with our affiliates (such as NPR, PBS, our program co-producers, and other public broadcasting organizations) to support the development of their services. For example, NPR or PBS may access your IP address when you access their content through our site, which helps them to develop system-wide analysis and insights. When you make a donation, we may share your donation details and contact information with other public broadcasting organizations to help them refine their fundraising efforts (not applicable to Visitors).

**2\. Other nonprofit entities**

From time to time, OPB exchanges mailing lists with other nonprofit groups to help us acquire new Members. We don’t share phone numbers, email addresses, or donation information. All OPB staff and any third party acting as agent for OPB are prohibited from selling, renting, leasing, lending, trading, giving, donating, transferring, or otherwise exchanging or making available OPB’s membership or donor lists to/with, or acquiring such lists from, any candidate for public office, political parties, or committees or organizations that solicit funds for use in political campaigns.

**3\. Service providers**

OPB engages a variety of trusted service providers to perform tasks and collect information on behalf of OPB. For example:

  * _Payment processors_ process donations and product orders using your bank or payment card information (not applicable to Visitors).

  * _Marketing companies_ collect and access your contact information solely so they can deliver newsletters, promotions, and other content from OPB.

  * _Fulfillment_ _companies_ need your contact information so they can send thank-you gifts and process your product orders (not applicable to Visitors).

  * _Analytics companies_ collect information and study how users interact with our services and deliver reports to OPB. They may also share personal information with each other in order for OPB to gain new insights on user behavior.

  * _Lookup service companies_ help ensure that our information is accurate by cross-referencing your information with other databases.

These service providers have limited access to your personal information only to perform the tasks on OPB’s behalf. They are contractually obligated not to share or disclose your personal information for any other purpose.

**4\. Other third parties**

In limited circumstances, OPB may share limited portions of your personal information with third parties, who may use your personal information to market relevant products and services to you. For example:

  * We may include limited portions of Members’ personal information in databases that are used to cross-reference data about Members from other sources. Other nonprofits and companies may subscribe to these databases to obtain your personal information.

  * We may share data about your preferences with third parties so they can send you pertinent content and offers.

**B. Other reasons we may share your personal information**

**1\. Transfer or assignment in connection with business changes or bankruptcy**

In the event of a merger, acquisition, reorganization, bankruptcy or other sale of all or a portion of our assets, any user information owned or controlled by us may be one of the assets transferred to third parties. Any successor entity will abide by the terms of this Privacy Policy with respect to personal information collected while this Privacy Policy was in effect. However, any information you submit or that is collected after this type of transfer may be subject to a new privacy policy adopted by the successor entity.

**2\. Response to subpoenas or court orders or to protect our rights**

We may disclose your information to government authorities or third parties if:

  * We are required to do so by law, or in response to a subpoena or court order, if a response is consistent with our integrity as a news organization

  * We believe in our sole discretion that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect against fraud, or to protect our property or other rights or those of other users of the services, third parties or the public at large

  * We believe that you have abused a service by using it to attack or gain unauthorized access to a system or to engage in spamming or other conduct that violates applicable laws or our Terms of Use

**3\. Your consent**

In some cases, we may ask for permission to use or share your personal information in ways not addressed by this Privacy Policy. For example, we may ask to disclose your name to a friend when you email or otherwise share a story with that friend.

**C. Non-personal information**

We may share with a variety of third parties (and without restriction) information that does not identify you personally. In some instances, these third parties may be able to combine this aggregate information with other data they have about you (from sources other than OPB), or that they receive from third parties, in a manner that allows them to identify you personally.

### **IV. Your choices for how we collect and use your personal information**

You can control how – and how much – personal information we use. We provide various opt-out mechanisms for different types of communications. You can also refrain from providing personal information in the first place: there is no registration requirement to use most of our services, and you can always decide whether to provide certain personal information. You can contact us if you want to change the personal information we have about you.

**A. Opting out**

Most of the personal information that OPB collects is voluntary. For example, if you do not want us to collect your email address, you may communicate with us via phone instead. You may also opt out of various communications and information practices by doing the following:

  * You may manage your OPB subscriptions at <http://www.opb.org/about/newsletter/manage>.

  * To opt out of receiving automated emails from OPB, you can follow the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of each email.

  * To opt out of membership mailings or phone calls, you may contact our Member Center at [opb.org/contactus](https://www.opb.org/about/contactus/) or 1-800-241-8123.

  * To opt out of OPB sharing your mailing address with other nonprofit organizations, you may contact our Member Center at [opb.org/contactus](https://www.opb.org/about/contactus/) or 1-800-241-8123.

  * California residents have additional opt-out rights, as described in Section VII below.

As discussed above, OPB partners with certain analytics companies that may place cookies, tags, web beacons, or similar technologies on OPB’s services. Some of these technologies enable targeted advertising. These third parties may participate in programs that allow you to opt out of targeted advertising. To learn more and opt out, visit the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/#completed) and the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

**B. Do Not Track**

Your Internet browser and mobile device may allow you to adjust your browser settings so that “do not track” requests are sent to the websites you visit. Websites that are configured to respond to “do not track” requests may disable certain behavioral advertising technologies when a user enables “do not track” features on various web browsers. However, OPB does not respond to “do not track” signals at this time.

### **V. How OPB protects your personal information**

_We care about the security of your personal information and have taken reasonable steps to protect it. However, we cannot guarantee the absolute secrecy of your data._

OPB uses reasonable technical and contractual procedures to protect your personal information from loss or misuse. For example, we require service providers that access your personal information to abide by rigorous data security standards. In addition, all credit card numbers and checking account numbers submitted to the site are encrypted, which is the industry standard for information security and is used by more than 100,000 web sites in more than 50 countries. Any personal information you submit with your donation is encrypted using protocols that meet or exceed current industry standards. These standards are designed to ensure the best possible protection against interception and decryption of information sent through our secure connections. Your peace of mind and security are very important to us. If you do not feel comfortable submitting your financial information online, you can make your donation by calling OPB at 1-800-241-8123.

Despite these efforts, technology changes rapidly, and no data transmission or storage can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. We cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us.

### **VI. Children’s privacy**

_While we hope that you – as a parent or caregiver – will share OPB’s content with children, we don’t knowingly collect personal information about children._

OPB’s online services are not intended for users younger than 13. We do not knowingly collect contact information from children under the age of 13 without verifiable parental consent. If we become aware that a visitor under the age of 13 has submitted personal information without verifiable parental consent, we will remove his or her information from our files.

### **VII. Your California privacy rights**

_California residents may opt out of certain types of sharing._

If you are a California resident, you may ask OPB to refrain from sharing your personal information with certain for profit entities for their own marketing purposes. Please tell us your preferences by contacting us at [opb.org/contactus](https://www.opb.org/about/contactus/) or 1-800-241-8123.

### **VIII. Changes to this Privacy Policy**

_We will notify you when we change this Privacy Policy._

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we decide to make a material change in our Privacy Policy, we will post it on this page.

### **IX. How to contact us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our use of the information we collect from you in connection with the services, go online at [opb.org/contactus ](https://www.opb.org/about/contactus/)or call 1-800-241-8123.
